Guide to the Richard Wright Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1933-1977; Series I; 38; (92 boxes)
  - STORIES
    - "The Man Who Built a House," draft fragment, typescript, n.d. (Box 87, Folder 1057)
    - "The Man Who Killed A Shadow," printed version (as "L'homme qui tua une ombre"), Les Lettres Françaises, 1946 Oct 4
      See: Oversize. Box 122, folder 1956
    - "The Man Who Led the Sheep," draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 87, Folder 1058)
    - "The Man Who Lived Underground," printed version (as L'homme qui vivait sous terre), Les Temps Modernes, with clipping, 1951 Jul-Aug (Box 87, Folder 1059)
    - "The Man Who Saw the Flood"
      - Printed version (as "Der Mann, der das Hochwasser sah), Deutsche Zeitung, 1961 Sep 23-24 (Box 87, Folder 1060)
      - Printed version (as "Der Mann, der das Hochwasser sah), Rundschau-Wochenende, 1962 May 12-13
    - [Pimp Situation], draft, typescript (Box 87, Folder 1061)
    - "Rite of Passage," drafts, typescript and carbon, corrected [with notes] (Box 87, Folder 1062-1064)
    - "Rite of Passage," drafts, typescript and carbon, corrected [with notes] (Box 88, Folder 1065-1068)
    - "Song of the Bleeding Throat," drafts, holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 88, Folder 1069-1071)
    - "A Strange Girl," draft, typescript, corrected [with outline], n.d. (Box 88, Folder 1072)
      See also: Proposals, [Celebration], Box 85, folder 983
    - "When the World Was Red," drafts, holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 88, Folder 1073)
  - TRANSLATIONS
    - Diop, Alioune, [Statement of aims for Presence Africaine ] translated and adapted [in collaboration with Thomas Diop] as "Niam N'Goura or Presence Africaine's Raison D'être"
      - Notes, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 1074)
      - Printed version, Presence Africaine, 1947 Nov-Dec
        [With original text by Diop]
      - Announcement of article and subsequent association of Wright with Présence Africaine - clipping, 1948-49 (Box 88, Folder 1075)
        See also: Oversize, Box 122, folder 1957
    - Sartre, Jean-Paul, L'être et le néant [Introduction], draft, typescript, corrected (Box 88, Folder 1076)
    - [Unknown author], Foreword and General Introduction [to Karl Jaspers]
      - Draft, holograph and typescript (Box 88, Folder 1077)
      - Background clipping, 1955 Sep 18
  - OTHER WRITINGS
    - [Invitation to a speaker written by Wrighton behalf of the Authors' League of America], drafts, holograph and typescript, corrected, 1947 (Box 88, Folder 1078)
    - [Loyalty oath for Communist Party members regarding U.S. war effort], drafts, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 1079)
    - [Questions on Leopold Senghor], draft, typescript carbon, [1956] (Box 88, Folder 1080)
    - "Reactions to the script of 'La Putain Respectueuse'," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 1081)
      See also: Blurbs, etc. - Introductory note to The Respectful Prostitute, Box 8, folder 195
    - "Spiritual Illness" [draft of a reply to a critic (probably of his "What You Don't Know Won't Hurt You)], draft, typescript, corrected, [1942?] (Box 88, Folder 1082)
    - "United We Stand, Divided We Fall," [Lenin memorial pageant], synopsis and verses for prologue, draft, typescript, corrected [with notes], [ca. 1937?] (Box 88, Folder 1083)
  - WRITINGS OF OTHERS
    - Anderson, Edith
      - "Bargain Basement," [story], typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 1084)
      - "For Willie McGhee" [poem], typescript, n.d.
    - Appadorai, A.
      - The Bandung Conference [booklet, autographed to Richard Wright], 1956 (Box 89, Folder 1085)
    - Arendt, Hannah
      - "The Mob and the Elite," [article] printed version, Partisan Review (Box 89, Folder 1086)
    - Baldwin, James
      - Go Tell It on the Mountain, novel, draft (incomplete), typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 1086a)
      - "Princes and Powers," [article] printed version, Encounter, 1957 Jan (Box 89, Folder 1087)
    - Borneman, Ernest
      - "A Draft Prospectus on American Negro Film Production: Finance and Story Aspects," typescript (Box 89, Folder 1087a)
      - "A History of American Negro Music" [outline], typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 1087b)
    - Burke, James
      - "My Wonderful Home Town" [story], typescript carbon [includes cover letter from Burke to Richard Wright 1953 Aug 10] (Box 89, Folder 1088)
    - Bush, Roger Dean
      - "Cancer Agony" [poem], typescript photostat, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 1089)
    - Carlson, Esther
      - "The Radiant Wood" [story], typescript and printed version from Atlantic Monthly (Box 89, Folder 1090)
    - Cayton, Horace
      - "Frightened Children of Frightened Parents" [article on Richard Wright], typescript carbon, 1945 Feb 22 (Box 89, Folder 1090a)
      - "Negro Housing in Chicago," [article] Social Action, 1940 Apr 15 (Box 89, Folder 1091)
    - Charles, Charles V.
      - "Optimism and Frustration in the American Negro" [article], offprint, 1942 (Box 89, Folder 1092)
    - Edwards, Doris
      - "We Native Sons" [poem], printed version, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 1093)
    - Everts, Lillian
      - "While the Past Burns" [chapbook], 1945 (Box 89, Folder 1094)
    - Farrell, James T.
      - "Tolstoy's War and Peace ," printed version, University of Kansas City Review (Box 89, Folder 1095)
    - Frazier, E. Franklin
      - "Human, All Too Human" [essay], typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 1096)
    - Gibson, Richard A. and James Baldwin
      - "Two Protests against Protest," printed version, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 1097)
    - Gold, Mike
      - "Change the World" [open letter to Richard Wright], printed version, Daily Worker, 1940 Sep 29 (Box 89, Folder 1098)
    - Good, Thomas
      - "Orange" [poem], typescript, [1948] (Box 89, Folder 1099)
    - Goodman, Randolph G.
      - "Fire and Cloud" [radio play adapted from Richard Wright's story from Uncle Tom's Children ], script, typescript and carbon (includes introduction by Wright) (Box 89, Folder 1100)
    - Guérin, Daniel
      - "La langue Créole aux Antilles," typescript corrected, and "Les cultes africaines, Première forme de résistance," typescript carbon, corrected (Box 89, Folder 1100a)
    - Hale, Nancy
      - "One of the Boys" [story], typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 1101)
    - Harris, Mark
      - "Day and Night" [poem], typescript (Box 89, Folder 1102)
    - James, C.L.R.
      - "Toussaint Louverture" [play], typescript, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 1102a)
    - Johnson, Janice
      - "Native Son: A Tribute to Richard Wright's Book" [poem], printed version, [1941?] (Box 89, Folder 1103)
    - Karpman, Ben
      - "Insecurity, Aggression and Struggle for Power: Reflections of a Psychiatrist on Humanity and the World Crisis" [essay], typescript, corrected (with commentary notes in an unidentified hand) (Box 89, Folder 1104)
      - [Comment on "Insecurity, Aggression and Struggle for Power"?] by unidentified reviewer, typescript (Box 89, Folder 1105)
      - [Transcripts of psychiatric sessions dealing with unidentified patient's dreams and Karpman's[?] commentary], typescript carbon (Box 89, Folder 1106-1107)
      - Students of Karpman
        - Psychological studies of Native Son, typescripts, corrected, 1940 (Box 90, Folder 1108-1110)
        - "Psychogenetic Studies in Race Psychology" (collection of essays compiled by Karpman), typescripts and carbon, corrected, ca. 1935-48 (Box 90, Folder 1111-1116)
    - Kreymborg, Alfred
      - "The Old South (For Richard Wright)" [poem], printed version, The Crisis, 1941 Jan (Box 91, Folder 1117)
    - Lowe, Ramona
      - "Fire and Cloud" (play adapted from Richard Wright's story from Uncle Tom's Children ), script, typescript carbon, corrected (Box 91, Folder 1118)
    - Mphahlele, Ezekiel
      - "Out of Africa: A Negro Writer's Reply," galley proof (for Encounter, with note from Melvin J. Lasky), 1959 Aug 16 (Box 91, Folder 1119)
    - Myrdal, Gunnar
      - "Development and Underdevelopment: A Note on the Mechanism of National and International Economic Inequality," typescript carbon, 1955 (Box 91, Folder 1120)
      - "The Research Work of the Secretariat of the Economic Commission for Europe" typescript carbon, 1956 Feb
    - Negri, Dante
      - "Ti Badrone" [poem], holograph, n.d. (Box 91, Folder 1121)
    - Owen, Charles
      - "Negroes and the War" [article]
        See: Oversize, Box 122, folder 1958
    - Pikowsky, Theodora
      - "Tarbaby's Dawn: A Critique" [essay], typescript, n.d. (Box 91, Folder 1122)
    - Pivano, Fernanda
      - [Introduction to an Anthology of Negro Literature], typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 91, Folder 1123)
      - [On the American Racial Situation], typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 91, Folder 1124)
    - Potts, Paul
      - "Not Since Dante: Ignazio Silone, A Footnote" [article], galley proof, corrected, n.d. (Box 91, Folder 1125)
    - Replansky, Naomi
      - [Four miscellaneous poems: "Detective Story", "A Good Days's Work", "The Man From Mars Goes Traveling" and "This Way of Loving"], typescript (Box 91, Folder 1126)
      - "Poems in Progress" [collection], typescript, 1933-40
      - "Ring Song" [collection of poems], typescript, 1939-40
    - Rivers, Conrad Kent
      - "To Richard Wright" [poem], printed version, The Antioch Review, 1960-61 Winter (Box 91, Folder 1127)
    - Roudy, Pierre
      - "Le Numero" [play], typescript photocopy, [1967] (Box 91, Folder 1128)
    - S., D.
      - "Uprising" [poem], typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 91, Folder 1129)
    - Sapin, Louis
      - "Papa Bon Dieu" [play], mimeograph script (with fragment of music, "Bicycle Thieves" and "Spread Joy" in an unidentified hand inserted as a bookmark) (Box 91, Folder 1130)
    - Semsel, George
      - "Body" [poem], typescript, n.d. (Box 91, Folder 1131)
    - Shattuck, R.
      - "Blue-Black" [poem], typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 91, Folder 1132)
      - "Through Dust" [poem], typescript carbon
    - Sinclair, Jo [Ruth Seid]
      - "The Hours" [poem], typescript, n.d. (Box 91, Folder 1133)
    - Stewart, David Ogden, Mrs.
      - [Press release on "Art of the Stars"], n.d. (Box 91, Folder 1134)
    - [Stockhower, Harry?]
      - "In the Fascist Styx: The Fate of Native Sons: From Remarque to Richard Wright" [essay], typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 91, Folder 1135)
    - Thornhill, J. Enrique
      - "The Problem of the British West Indian Student in the U.S.A." [essay], typescript, corrected (Box 91, Folder 1136)
    - Torr, Hannah
      - "The Settlement House Window" [story], typescript (Box 91, Folder 1137)
    - Vaal, Hans de
      - "Richard Wright - In Memoriam" [article], typescript (with cover letter to Julia Wright), 1961 Mar (Box 91, Folder 1138)
    - Ward, Theodore
      - "Bright and Morning Star" (play adapted from Richard Wright's story from Uncle Tom's Children ), script, typescript carbon, corrected (Box 91, Folder 1139)
    - Webb, Constance
      - Richard Wright: A Biography, typescript, photocopy, n.d. (Box 92, Folder 1140-1146)
    - White, John Graham
      - "Richard Wright: Black Boy: Analyzed and Interpreted with the Aid of the Need-Press Theory of Personality" [essay], typescript carbon (with cover letter), 1949 (Box 92, Folder 1147)
    - White, Ralph K.
      - "Black Boy: A Value Analysis" [essay] (Box 92, Folder 1148)
    - Various
      - Richard Wright -- American People's Artist, proposal for book of critical essays, n.d. (Box 92, Folder 1149)
    - Unidentified
      - "Bataille du Rail" [dialogues for film script], typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 92, Folder 1150)
      - "Dirge" [poem], typescript carbon, 1945 May 5
      - "Exodus" [film], synopsis, typescript carbon, n.d.
      - "How Richard Wright Found His Editor" [article], typescript carbon (Box 92, Folder 1151)
      - "Innocent Betrayal" [story], typescript carbon, n.d.
      - "Letters from a Sharecropper" [with an introductory note by Richard Wright], ca. 1937 (Box 92, Folder 1152)
      - "Manifeste de l'Epiphanisme" [essay], typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 92, Folder 1153)
      - [Negroes in Chicago] [essay fragment], typescript carbon, n.d.
      - "Passion Lost" [play], summary, typescript, n.d. (Box 92, Folder 1154)
      - "Passport for Adam and Eve" [essay], typescript carbon
      - "Richard Wright" [essay in French], typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 92, Folder 1155)
      - "Shadow of the Valley" [essay], typescript, n.d.
      - "The Starry Heavens Above" [poem], typescript, n.d. (Box 92, Folder 1156)
      - "Success" [poem], typescript, photocopy, n.d.
      - [Three leaves of typescript carbon of dialogue in French] [Story fragment], holograph, n.d.
- Correspondence, 1934-1975; Series II; 7.5; (18 boxes)
  Series II, Correspondence, is divided into two subseries, Personal Correspondence and Third-Party Correspondence, each of which is arranged alphabetically by name.
  - PERSONAL CORRESPONDENCE
    - "A" general, 1935-60 (Box 93, Folder 1157-1158)
    - Aaron, Abraham J., 1937-45 (Box 93, Folder 1159)
    - Abraham Lincoln Brigade, 1942 (Box 93, Folder 1160)
    - Abrahams, Peter, 1946-48 (Box 93, Folder 1161)
    - Acum, Ltd., 1960 (Box 93, Folder 1162)
    - Africa Magazine, 1959 (Box 93, Folder 1163)
    - Afro-American Newspapers, 1941-56 (Box 93, Folder 1164)
    - A. H. Gruetzmacher & Co., 1942 (Box 93, Folder 1165)
    - Alfred A. Knopf, Inc., 1935-57 (Box 93, Folder 1166)
    - Algren, Nelson, 1939-45 (Box 93, Folder 1167)
    - Alsberg, Henry G.
      See: Federal Writers' Project, Box 97, folder 1331
    - American Civil Liberties Union, 1941-45 (Box 93, Folder 1168)
    - American Committee for Friendship with the Soviet Union, 1941 (Box 93, Folder 1169)
    - American Council on Race Relations, 1945-46 (Box 93, Folder 1170)
    - American Council on Soviet Relationships, 1940-41 (Box 93, Folder 1171)
    - American Peace Mobilization, 1940-41 (Box 93, Folder 1172)
    - American Society of African Culture, 1946-59 (Box 93, Folder 1173)
    - American Theatre Association of Paris, 1959-60 (Box 93, Folder 1174)
    - America's Town Meeting of the Air, 1945 May (Box 93, Folder 1175)
    - Anderson, Edith, 1947-51 (Box 93, Folder 1176)
    - Anderson, Marion, 1938, 1943 (Box 93, Folder 1177)
    - Ann Watkin, Inc., 1937-38 (Box 93, Folder 1178)
    - Antioch Review, 1944, 1947 (Box 93, Folder 1179)
    - Antonetto, Irma
      See: Associazione Culturale Italiana, Box 93, folder 1188
    - Argentina Sono Film, S.A.C.I., 1949-51 (Box 93, Folder 1180)
    - Argus de la Presse, 1948-51 (Box 93, Folder 1181)
    - Armattoe, Marina, 1953-54 (Box 93, Folder 1182)
    - Armattoe, R.E., 1953
    - Arnaud, Marthe, 1948 (Box 93, Folder 1183)
    - Arnoldo Mondadore, Editore, 1946-60 (Box 93, Folder 1184)
    - Arrington, Winston, 1955-60 (Box 93, Folder 1185)
    - Artists League of America, 1942 (Box 93, Folder 1186)
    - Arvin, Newton
      See: Yaddo, Box 108, folder 1702
    - Ashton, Sylvia
      See: P.M. Daily, Box 104, folder 1549
    - Associated Negro Press, 1937-49 (Box 93, Folder 1187)
    - Associazione Culturale Italiana, 1950-51 (Box 93, Folder 1188)
    - Astre, G., 1946-[48?] (Box 93, Folder 1189)
    - Aswell, Edward, 1955 Aug 21
      See: Series I, PROPOSALS - [Celebration] for letter from Wright explaining his work on "Celebration of Life," When the World was Red," and "A Strange Daughter", Box 85, folder 983
      See also: Doubleday & Co. Inc., Box 96, folder 1301
      See also: Eugene F. Saxton Memorial Trust, Box 96, folder 1319
      See also: Harper & Brothers Publishers, Box 98, folder 1378
      See also: McGraw-Hill Book Company, Inc., Box 101, folder 1459
    - Atkinson, Brooks
      See: Henry F Winslow, Sr., Box 108, folder 1690
    - Atlantic Monthly, 1940-52 (Box 93, Folder 1190)
    - Attaway, Ruth, 1941-42 (Box 94, Folder 1191)
    - Attaway, William, 1941
    - The Author Meets the Critics, 1945-47 (Box 94, Folder 1192)
    - Author's League of America - Author's Guild, 1939-58 (Box 94, Folder 1193)
    - Author's League of America - Dramatist's Guild, 1940, 1949 (Box 94, Folder 1194)
    - A. W. Sijthoff's Uitgeversmaatschappij N.V., 1948-55 (Box 94, Folder 1195)
    - "B" general, 1936-60 (Box 94, Folder 1196-1198)
    - Baker, Keith, 1940-41 (Box 94, Folder 1199)
    - Balch, Jack, 1935, 1942 (Box 94, Folder 1200)
    - Baldwin, James, 1945 Dec 27 (Box 94, Folder 1201)
    - Baldwin, Roger
      See: Series III, Franco-American Fellowship, Box 112, folder 1780
    - Bancroft, Mary, 1947 Aug 7 (Box 94, Folder 1202)
    - Barber, Ruth, 1946-56 (Box 94, Folder 1203)
      includes letter from André (Tao-Kim-Hai)
    - Barclay Disques, 1960-61 (Box 94, Folder 1204)
    - Barnett, Claude A.
      See: Associated Negro Press, Box 93, folder 1187
    - Barry, Joseph
      See: Gertrude Stein, Box 106, folder 1619
    - Bauman, Frances, 1939-45 (Box 94, Folder 1205)
    - Beach, Sylvia, 1947-49 (Box 94, Folder 1206)
      includes typescript carbon of "The Ulysses Subscribers" by Beach
    - Beauvoir, Simone de, 1947, n.d. (Box 94, Folder 1206a)
    - Belin, Marie-Rose, n.d. (Box 94, Folder 1207)
    - Bennett, Gwendolyn, 1939-41 (Box 94, Folder 1208)
    - Bercut, Annette, 1948-50 (Box 94, Folder 1209)
    - Bervall, Miss, n.d. (Box 94, Folder 1210)
      [draft of letter from Wright]
    - Bessie, Simon Michael
      See: Harper & Brothers Publishers, Box 98, folder 1378
    - Birdoff, Harry, 1941 (Box 94, Folder 1211)
    - Black, Hugo Lafayette, 1941 (Box 94, Folder 1212)
    - Blackman, Saul, 1952-53 (Box 94, Folder 1213)
    - Blake, Christophe, 1946 (Box 94, Folder 1214)
    - Bliven, Bruce
      See: New Republic, Box 102, folder 1498
    - Boas, Franz, 1940-41 (Box 94, Folder 1215)
    - The Bodley Head, 1958-59 (Box 94, Folder 1216)
    - Bokanowski, Hélène, 1947, n.d. (Box 94, Folder 1217)
    - Bokanowski, Micheal, 1947-55
    - Bolster, Esther Carlson, 1946-47 (Box 94, Folder 1218)
    - Bompiano, Valentino
      See: Valentino Bompiano & C., Box 107, folder 1656
    - Bondy, François
      See: Preuves, Box 104, folder 1558
    - Bonniers Folkbibliothek, 1955-58 (Box 94, Folder 1219)
    - Bontemps, Arna, 1937-60 (Box 94, Folder 1220)
    - Book Find Club, 1943-54 (Box 94, Folder 1221)
    - Book of the Month Club, 1945 (Box 94, Folder 1222)
    - Books for Russia, 1945 (Box 94, Folder 1223)
    - The Bookshop, A Consumer Cooperative, 1937-41 (Box 94, Folder 1224)
    - Borneman, Ernest, 1942-47 (Box 94, Folder 1225)
    - Bowen, Merlin, 1938, 1940 (Box 94, Folder 1226)
    - Boyea, Samuel, 1941-45 (Box 94, Folder 1227)
    - Boyle, Kay, 1948-56 (Box 94, Folder 1228)
    - Bradley, Jenny, 1946-58 (Box 94, Folder 1229)
    - Brand, Millen, 1937-40 (Box 94, Folder 1230)
    - Braziller, George, 1949 Jun 14 (Box 94, Folder 1231)
      See also: Book Find Club, Box 94, folder 1221
    - Bread Loaf Writer's Conference, 1945-46 (Box 94, Folder 1232)
    - Brieux, Jean Jacques
      See: Présence Africaine, Box 104, folder 1557
    - British Broadcasting Corporation, 1947-59 (Box 94, Folder 1233)
    - Brooks, Gwendolyn, 1945-46 (Box 94, Folder 1234)
    - Brooks, Richard, n.d. (Box 94, Folder 1235)
    - Brown, Basil Breven
      See: Oversize, Box 122, folder 1959
    - Brown, Joe C., 1938-59 (Box 95, Folder 1236)
    - Brown, Oril, 19[35?]-48 (Box 95, Folder 1237)
    - Brown, Sterling, 1938-57 (Box 95, Folder 1238)
    - Browning, Alice, 1942, 1945, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 1239)
      See also: Negro Story Magazine, Box 102, folder 1493
    - Buchet, Edmond
      See: Editions Corréa & Cie., Box 97, folder 1308
    - Buckmaster, Henrietta, 1938-47 (Box 95, Folder 1240)
    - Bundy, Lucile, 1940, 1945 (Box 95, Folder 1241)
    - Burke, Sara Roberts, 1938-45, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 1242)
    - Burnett, Whit
      See: Story magazine, Box 106, folder 1625
    - Burnshaw, Stanley
      See: New Masses, Box 102, folder 1497
    - "C" general, 1935-61 (Box 95, Folder 1243-1245)
    - Calmann-Lévy, Editeurs, 1958-60 (Box 95, Folder 1246)
    - Calmer, Alan, 1934, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 1247)
      includes "Report of Second National Conference John Reed Clubs, Chicago, Sept. 26-30, 1934"
    - Camerana, Giancarlo
    - Camus, Albert, [1947?] Oct 16 (Box 95, Folder 1248)
    - Canby, Henry Seidel, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 1249)
    - Canby, Marion G.
      See: Greater New York Chorus, Box 98, folder 1362
      See: A New Chorus, Box 102, folder 1495
    - Canfield, Cass
    - Carmon, Walt, 1935-41 (Box 95, Folder 1250)
      Includes letters by M. Apletin and T. Rokotov
    - Caro, Herbert, 1937, 1944, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 1251)
    - Carter, Elmer A., 1947-57 (Box 95, Folder 1252)
    - Carter, Micheal
      See: Milton Smith, Box 106, folder 1613
    - Cattell, Elizabeth [née Littell], 1940-46 (Box 95, Folder 1253)
    - Cayton, Horace Roscoe, 1940-51 (Box 95, Folder 1254-1255)
    - Cerf, Bennett
      See: Books for Russia, Box 94, folder 1223
      See: Random House, Inc., Box 105, folder 1570
    - Chapman, Abraham and Belle, 1936-1945 (Box 96, Folder 1256)
      Includes letter from "Mannie"
    - Chenal, Pierre, 1950-51 (Box 96, Folder 1257)
    - Chicago Daily News, 1940 (Box 96, Folder 1258)
    - Citizen's Committee for Harry Bridges, 1941 (Box 96, Folder 1259)
    - Citizen's Committee to Free Earl Browder, 1941-42 (Box 96, Folder 1260)
    - Claassen Verlag, GmBH, 1956-58 (Box 96, Folder 1261)
      See also: Kongress für die Freiheit der Kultur, Box 100, folder 1422
    - Clarke, G. Belfield, 1956-60 (Box 96, Folder 1262)
    - Clemens, Cyril, 1938-59 (Box 96, Folder 1263)
    - Clifford, Jay, 1952, 1954 (Box 96, Folder 1264)
    - Cocteau, Jean, 195?, n.d. (Box 96, Folder 1265)
    - Coe, Ethel B., 1940-46 (Box 96, Folder 1266)
    - Coen, Fabio
      See: Fabio Coen Agenzia Letteraria, Box 97, folder 1322
    - Columbia Pictures Corporation, 1944-45 (Box 96, Folder 1267)
    - Columbia University, 1940-45 (Box 96, Folder 1268)
    - Combat, 1957, n.d. (Box 96, Folder 1269)
    - Commins, Saxe
    - Communist Party, U.S.A., 1939 Sep 22 (Box 96, Folder 1270)
    - Congrès pour la liberté de la Culture, 1955-57 (Box 96, Folder 1271)
    - Connolly, Cyril, 1946 Aug 7 (Box 96, Folder 1272)
    - Conroy, Jack, 1936-44 (Box 96, Folder 1273)
    - Cook, Mercer, 1956-59 (Box 96, Folder 1274)
    - Cooper, Robert L.
      See: Wiltwyck School for Boys, Inc., Box 108, folder 1688
    - Corey, George, 1938 May (Box 96, Folder 1275)
    - Council on Race and Caste in World Affairs (American Information Committee on Race and Caste, Inc.), 1956-57 (Box 96, Folder 1276)
    - Cousins, Norman
      See: Saturday Review, Box 106, folder 1598
    - Cowley, Malcolm
    - Crisis
      See: James W. Ivy, Box 99, folder 1404
    - Crosby, Caresse, 1945 (Box 96, Folder 1277)
    - Crossman, R.H.S., 1948-60 (Box 96, Folder 1278)
    - Cuevas de Vera, Tolá, 1950, 1955 (Box 96, Folder 1279)
    - Cullen, Countee, 1938-40 (Box 96, Folder 1280)
    - Cunard, Nancy, n.d. (Box 96, Folder 1281)
    - Curtiss, Willa, 1950-52 (Box 96, Folder 1282)
    - "D" general, 1938-60 (Box 96, Folder 1283)
    - Daily Worker, 1940-44 (Box 96, Folder 1284)
    - Dalton, Edward H., n.d. (Box 96, Folder 1285)
    - Damas (Letters of introduction for Richard Wright), 1946 Apr 26 (Box 96, Folder 1286)
    - Danquah, Eric, 1949 Jun 6 (Box 96, Folder 1287)
    - Danquah, Joseph B., 1954 Sep 28 (Box 96, Folder 1288)
    - David, George
      See: Harper's Magazine, Box 99, folder 1384
    - Davis, Ben, Jr., 1940-43 (Box 96, Folder 1289)
      See also: Daily Worker, Box 96, folder 1284
    - Davis, Frank Marshall
    - Davis, John A.
      See: Council on Race and Caste in World Affairs, Box 96, folder 1276
    - Deei, Kaie, 1940-42 (Box 96, Folder 1290)
    - [EMPTY FOLDER] (Box 96, Folder 1291)
    - Demby, William, n.d. (Box 96, Folder 1292)
    - Dennis Dobson, Ltd., Publishers, 1955-56 (Box 96, Folder 1293)
    - DeVries, Peter, 1945 Jan 29 (Box 96, Folder 1294)